## **George Salteris**

https://georgesalteris.me/

www.linkedin.com/in/georgesalteris

### **Summary**

Software engineer with three years of experience in coding and testing, seeking a job in the intersection of data and computer science. Strong hands-on experience of Java, Python, PHP, SQL, and object-oriented development. An enthusiastic team player and creative thinker. Enjoy investigating "chaotic" large scale datasets and extracting important business information by gaining full insight into the underlying trends. Excellent skills in high-level programming and aptitude for adaptation to new programming languages.

### **Education**

## W. P. Carey School of Business at Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ

May 2019

Master of Science in Business Analytics GPA: 3.81/4.0

Project: "Measuring engagement of the Notebowl social learning platform for white paper results"

Dataset Type: User engagement on the learning platform along with their score. Size: 700,000 rows.

Techniques: Employed regression techniques using Python to predict if the user engagement correlated with user's grades.

Outcome: Work in progress.

### Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering at University of Ioannina, Ioannina, Greece

July 2018

Master of Science in Computer Science & Engineering GPA: 6.39/10

Thesis: "Phenotype Prediction Using Genotype Information"

Dataset Type: Genomic data with 0.07% having Cancer Melanoma. Size: 272,176 patients, out of 11TB unstructured genomic dataset. Techniques: Employed a five-step pipeline for data transformation, then applied logistic regression and SVM techniques using Python.

Outcome: Achieved 89% accuracy and 73% recall on cancer prediction based on tailor made genomic features.

# Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering at University of Ioannina, Ioannina, Greece

July 2018

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science & Engineering GPA: 6.39/10

### **Professional Qualifications**

- Machine Learning Techniques
- Data Wrangling & Visualization
- Data Management

- Decision Analysis
- Analysis, Design and Implementation of Databases
- C, Python, SQL, Java, JavaScript, PHP, Ionic, HTML, CSS, R.
- AngularJs, Lucene, D3.js, Laravel, Tableau, VueJs, Spark, Chart.js.

### **Professional Experience**

Web Developer

Aug 2019 – Oct 2019

Vonage, Scottsdale. AZ

- Developed the full-stack application using Laravel, SQL, HTML 5, and Javascript for an internal website to monitor the task of the call center.
- Designed and created analytical dashboards to generate reports and graph visualizations of performance metrics.

Data Scientist - Intern Mar 2019 – Jul 2019

FetchRev, Tempe, AZ

- Provided insights to help the business segments and stakeholders optimize their targeted advertisement.
- Developed a machine learning model using collaborate filtering and clustering techniques to identify relationships in data.

Software Engineer Dec 2017 – Aug 2018

Hellenic Army, Athens, Greece

- Developed the full stack application using Laravel, SQL, HTML 5, Javascript and VueJS for two applications for the Greek Army.
- Designed and created MySQL Database for a web and mobile application to assist military personnel in finding available housing.
- Leveraged RESTful APIs to integrate the database and backend components with the mobile application including adhering to ISO 27001.

### **Software Engineer-Team Manager**

Dec 2017 - Jan 2019

VNimbus P.C, Athens, Greece

- Led a team of three engineers tasked with developing a platform for event management and reservations using Laravel, HTML 5 and VueJS.
- Designed and deployed websites using Laravel and HTML 5, for several industries including construction, hospitality and psychometrics.

### Junior Software Engineer

Oct 2016 - Nov 2017

Tooristas.com, Athens, Greece

- Designed front end administration (content management) and business panel using Angular JS for event management businesses.
- Assisted in backend issues and developed several APIs to update the MySQL database.